Guide to the Brooks McNamara Papers MSS 162
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Subject Files, 69684
  - Theatre [misc.]: Clippings, articles, photocopies, theatre-related listings, newsletters, catalogs., undated; 69732 (Box 28, Folder 490)
  - [Theatre Journals]: Theatre Quarterly vol.1, no.3 (1971); Theatre Forum no.11 (Summer/Fall 1997); Theatre Design and Technology (Spring 1989)., undated; 69731 (Box 28, Folder 491)
  - Theatre Postcards and Pictures: Photographs, postcards, programs., undated; 69730 (Box 29, Folder 492)
    Offsite Barcode: 31142042233984
  - Theatrical Newspapers: Newsletters., undated; 69729 (Box 29, Folder 493)
  - (Tent Shows) Toby and Tom Shows: Clippings, articles, photocopies, correspondence, script, BM notes., undated; 69728 (Box 29, Folder 494)
  - Toby Show: Clippings, articles, photocopies, newsletters, correspondence, student work., undated; 69727 (Box 29, Folder 495)
  - Tournaments: Articles, photocopies, course materials, bibliographies, student work., undated; 69726 (Box 29, Folder 496)
  - Tourism I: Clippings, articles, photocopies; prospectus for book, "Tourist Productions," by Barbara Kirshenblatt-Gimblett and Edward Bruner (1985)., undated; 69725 (Box 29, Folder 497)
  - Tourism II: Clippings, articles, photocopies, brochures, guides, pamphlets; draft, "Tourism: Performing Ethnographic Tropes" by Barbara Kirshenblatt-Gimblett and Edward Bruner (1988)., undated; 69724 (Box 29, Folder 498)
  - Tourism III: Clippings, articles, photocopies, brochures, guides, pamphlets, postcards; manuscript, "The Body in Water: Women in American Spa Culture," by Susan Slyomovics., undated; 69723 (Box 29, Folder 499)
  - Tourism IV: Clippings, articles, photocopies, brochures, guides, pamphlets, course syllabus., undated; 69722 (Box 29, Folder 500)
  - Toy Theatres: Clippings, photocopies, correspondence, gallery guide to the Hammond Museum's 1967 exhibition "Illusion and Reality"., undated; 69721 (Box 29, Folder 501)
  - Uncle Tom's Cabin I: Clippings, articles, photocopies, scripts, photographs; BM draft; catalog of source materials for Uncle Tom's Cabin., undated; 69720 (Box 29, Folder 502)
  - Uncle Tom's Cabin II: Articles, photocopies, scripts, BM notes., undated; 69719 (Box 29, Folder 503)
  - Variety Performances: Clippings, fliers., 1967-1987; 69718 (Box 30, Folder 504)
    Offsite Barcode: 31142042233992
  - Vaudeville I: Clippings, articles, photocopies, fliers, programs, correspondence, BM notes, interview questions, photographs., 1972-1994; 69717 (Box 30, Folder 505)
  - Vaudeville II: Clippings, articles, photocopies, fliers, programs, correspondence., 1975-1982; 69716 (Box 30, Folder 506)
  - Vaudeville III: Clippings, photocopies, programs., 1980-1982; 69715 (Box 30, Folder 507)
  - Vaudeville IV: Clippings, articles, photocopies, programs, script, correspondence, course syllabus, student work, interviews with vaudeville performers, BM notes., 1980-1993; 69714 (Box 30, Folder 508)
  - Vaudeville V - part I: Student work, photocopies, scripts., 1983-1988; 69713 (Box 30, Folder 509)
  - Vaudeville V - part II: Clippings, photocopies, programs, correspondence, student work., 1974-1991; 69712 (Box 30, Folder 510)
  - Vaudeville VI: Photocopies, programs, student work, correspondence., 1980-1988; 69711 (Box 30, Folder 511)
  - Vaudeville VII: Programs, publications from Radio City Music Hall., 1978-1995; 69710 (Box 30, Folder 512)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Playbills, 1983-1991, Radio City Music Hall]: Programs., 69709 (Box 30, Folder 513)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Playbills, 1982-1985, Rockettes Charity Events]: Programs., 69708 (Box 30, Folder 514)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Playbills, 1989-1994, Rockettes Easter Extravaganza]: Programs., 69707 (Box 30, Folder 515)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Playbills, 1985-1993, Rockettes Christmas Spectacular]: Programs., 69706 (Box 30, Folder 516)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Playbills, Siegfried and Roy]: Programs., undated; 69705 (Box 30, Folder 517)
  - Vaudeville VIII [Radio City Music Hall misc.]: Pamphlets, calendars., undated; 69704 (Box 30, Folder 518)
  - Vaudeville VIII: Course syllabus, conference program, "Vaudeville," play script by Laurence Carr., undated; 69703 (Box 31, Folder 519)
  - Vaudeville IX: Proposal to NEH for a "Survey of Vaudeville Performance on Film"., 1995; 69702 (Box 31, Folder 520)
  - Vaudeville IX: Articles, correspondence, student work, bibliographies., 1978-1995; 69701 (Box 31, Folder 521)
  - Vaudeville X: Edited draft of introduction., 1987; 69700 (Box 31, Folder 522)
  - Vaudeville XI [misc.]: Correspondence, photocopy, student work., 1970, 1995; 69699 (Box 31, Folder 523)
  - Ventriloquism: Student work, correspondence, fliers., 1976, 1989, 1993; 69698 (Box 31, Folder 524)
  - [Virtual Vietnam]: Clipping., 1994; 69697 (Box 31, Folder 525)
  - [Washington Square Players]: Article., 1965; 69696 (Box 31, Folder 526)
  - Weird Stuff: Clippings, articles, photocopies, postcards, pamphlets, fliers, correspondence, ephemera., undated; 69695 (Box 31, Folder 527)
  - Weird Stuff: Clippings., undated; 69694 (Box 31, Folder 528)
  - [Welfare State International]: Brochure., undated; 69693 (Box 31, Folder 529)
  - Wild West Show: Clippings, articles, photocopies, programs, postcards, bibliographies, student work., undated; 69692 (Box 31, Folder 530)
  - Oscar Wilde: Drafts of paper, "Oscar Wilde and the Aesthetes.", undated; 69691 (Box 31, Folder 531)
  - Bert Williams: Photocopies relating to "In Dahomey: a Negro Musical Comedy.", undated; 69690 (Box 31, Folder 532)
  - [Women in Performance]: Photocopy., undated; 69689 (Box 31, Folder 533)
  - Worker's Theater I: Articles., undated; 69688 (Box 31, Folder 534)
  - Worker's Theater II: Articles, photocopies., undated; 69687 (Box 31, Folder 535)
  - World's Fairs: Clippings, bibliography, postcards., undated; 69686 (Box 31, Folder 536)
  - Yiddish Theatre: Clippings, programs., undated; 69685 (Box 31, Folder 537)
  - Environmental (incl. restorations, role playing, etc.) [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Folk and Festival [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Med. [medicine] Show [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Melo. and Spect. [melodrama and spectacle] [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Minstrelsy [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Moral and Ed., Ents. [educational entertainments] [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Musical Th. [theater] [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Parade and Pag. [pageant], I [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Day of Jubilee [slides], undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - R3 Shoulder [film], 1918 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 3-4)
  - Coney Island [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
  - The Cake Eater reel [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
  - Good Old Five Cent Trolley Ride [film], 1905 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - The Making of Broncho Billy [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Gullse's Wayward Path [film], 1915 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Malkasian [video], undated (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Abbot & Costello "Who's on first" [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - R-1 Shoulder Arms [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - The St. James Mime [video], undated (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Deadly Turning [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Malkasian [video], undated (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Making a Living [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Grit of Girl Telegrapher [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - The Vagabond [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 20-21)
  - Lonedale Operator [film], undated (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Golden Age of the Theatre [sic] from Audio Rarities 2465 [audio], undated (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Vi-Ton-Ka [audio], 1983 (Box 37, Folder 24-25)
  - A National Theater: Interviews with Charles Dillingham A.C.I., San Francisco; Rudolph Bing, Metropolitan Opera, N.Y.; by Douglas Amir [sic] [audio], 1972 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Inteview: Jerome Lawrence by Seth Glassman [audio], 1972 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - The Mummy's Tomb [audio], undated (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Vitoaka [audio], 1983 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Yip Harburg: The Fellow Who Followed a Dream (NPR Journal, Spring 1981) [audiocassette] (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Gershwin Festival at Guild Hall "Love, Money, and Politics..." [audiocassette], 1986 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Gershwin Festival At Guild Hall: Classical and Classic [audiocassette], undated (Box 37, Folder 32-33)
  - Brooks McNamara slides [DVD-R], undated (Box 37, Folder 34-35)
  - Brooks McNamara Broadway Theaters [DVD-R], undated (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Parade and Pag. [pageant] II [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Parl. and Op. and Mech. [parlor and optical and mechanical] [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Theatres [sic], I [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 3-4)
  - Theatres [sic] B'way [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - B'way, II [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 6-7)
  - Tent Show and Tom [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Tournament [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Vaude [vaudeville] and Music Hall [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Sildes - Holding File, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Misc. [slides], undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
- Series II: Printed Materials., 69676
  Scope and Contents note
  Series II consists of a small number of books that accompany McNamara's subject files [7 folders].
  - Brown, Wesley. Darktown Strutters: a novel. New York: Cane Hill Press, 1994., 69683 (Box 31, Folder 538)
  - [Program:] Gloucester Tercentenary Pageant. Presented at Stage Fort Park, Gloucester, MA. August 28th and 30th, 1923., 69682 (Box 31, Folder 539)
  - Elliott, Eugene Clinton. A History of Variety-Vaudeville in Seattle: From the Beginning to 1914. Seattle: University of Washington Press, 1944., 69681 (Box 31, Folder 540)
  - McEvoy, Harry K. Knife Throwing: a Practical Guide. Tokyo, Japan; Rutland, VT, USA: Charles E. Tuttle Co., 1977., 69680 (Box 31, Folder 541)
  - Brooks, Peter F. Pearly Kings and Queens in Britain. London: Barry Rose Publishers, n.d., undated; 69679 (Box 31, Folder 542)
  - Mellor, G.J. Pom-Poms and Ruffles: The Story of Northern Seaside Entertainment. Yorkshire: Dalesman Publishing Company, Ltd., 1966. Clipping found inside the book, "Seasider's Diary: Confirming Blackpool's status," Evening Gazette, November 23, 1974., 1966, 1974; 69678 (Box 31, Folder 543)
  - MacKaye, Percy. The Roll Call: A Masque of the Red Cross. Washington, D.C.: National Headquarters American Red Cross, 1918. Copy from Glenn M. Loney., 69677 (Box 31, Folder 544)
- Series III: Talks, Papers., 69598
  Series III: Drafts, manuscripts, and notes for published papers and articles, as well as printouts for talks and speaking engagements [76 folders].
  - Brooks, M - Writings [unsorted]: BM notes, drafts, syllabi, photocopies., undated; 69675 (Box 31, Folder 545)
  - American Political Theatre - Talk: BM drafts., undated; 69674 (Box 31, Folder 546)
  - Edwin Booth's Legacy: Issue of journal, Nineteenth Century Theatre, vol.21, no.2 (Winter 1993)., 69673 (Box 31, Folder 547)
  - B.T.I. Introduction (Botto, Louis): BM introduction to Louis Botto, 2 pages., undated; 69672 (Box 31, Folder 548)
  - Burlingame Intro.: BM drafts of introduction to Lloyd Burlingame, 4 pages; invitation., undated; 69671 (Box 31, Folder 549)
  - The Busker: Photocopy of BM article; Newsletter of the Greater London Arts Association (September/October 1975)., 69670 (Box 31, Folder 550)
  - The Busker in London a Hundred Years Ago: BM draft., undated; 69669 (Box 31, Folder 551)
  - A Carnival City: Exhibition catalog, "The Country Fair Carnival: Where the Midway Meets the Grange," Chemung County Historical Society, Elmira, NY (1992)., 69668 (Box 31, Folder 552)
  - Catfish Dreamin': BM draft, "Catfish Dreamin' Meets the Medicine Show and Other Traditional Dreams and Illusions.", undated; 69667 (Box 31, Folder 553)
  - Celebrate Broadway Talk: Draft., undated; 69666 (Box 31, Folder 554)
  - The Circus and the New Theatre: Photocopies of BM article in Theatre Crafts (September 1972)., 69665 (Box 31, Folder 555)
  - Civic Pageantry in New York City: BM paper draft., undated; 69664 (Box 31, Folder 556)
  - Come on Over: BM article, "Come on Over: The rise and fall of the American amusement park," in Theatre Crafts (September 1977)., 69663 (Box 31, Folder 557)
  - A Congress of Wonders: BM article, "A Congress of Wonders: the Rise and Fall of the Dime Museum," in ESQ: A Journal of the American Renaissance (1974)., 69662 (Box 31, Folder 558)
  - David Douglass: Photocopy of BM article, "David Douglass and the Beginnings of American Theatre Architecture.", 1968; 69661 (Box 31, Folder 559)
  - Owen Davis and the Shubert Brothers: BM article in the newsletter of the Shubert Archive., 1995; 69660 (Box 31, Folder 560)
  - Deco Talk: BM draft of talk at the Lyceum Theatre., undated; 69659 (Box 31, Folder 561)
  - Defining Popular Entertainment: Drafts of BM keynote speech for the International Symposium on Popular Entertainment, CUNY Graduate Center, 1987., 69658 (Box 31, Folder 562)
  - Defining Popular Culture: BM article in Theatre History Studies volume 18 (1998)., 69657 (Box 31, Folder 563)
  - Double Gothic: the Scenography of Michael Kirby, an interview by Brooks McNamara: Photocopy of article in Theatre Design and Technology (Winter 1979)., 69656 (Box 31, Folder 564)
  - The English Playhouse in eighteenth-century America: Photocopy of BM article in The Connoisseur (September 1967)., 69655 (Box 31, Folder 565)
  - Environmental Theatre: BM notes, drafts, course materials., undated; 69654 (Box 31, Folder 566)
  - Feasts and Processions in the Urban Environment: BM article manuscript and photocopies., undated; 69653 (Box 31, Folder 567)
  - Films and Touring Films (Talk): BM talk, 3 pages., undated; 69652 (Box 31, Folder 568)
  - For Laughing Purposes Only: BM draft and photocopy of article, "For Laughing Purposes Only": The Literature of Popular Entertainment., undated; 69651 (Box 31, Folder 569)
  - "Friends of the Library" Speech: BM draft., undated; 69650 (Box 32, Folder 570)
  - "I'm Dr. Kronkhite."…: Drafts of BM talk, "I'm Dr. Kronkhite." "I'm Dubious.": The Health Professional in American Popular Comedy; poster for event (1987)., 69649 (Box 32, Folder 571)
  - The Invisible Theatre: BM drafts and photocopy of article, "The Invisible Theatre: The Folk and Festival Tradition in America.", 1978; 69648 (Box 32, Folder 572)
  - Jews and the American Theatre - Talk: BM drafts., undated; 69647 (Box 32, Folder 573)
  - Kirby Memorial Service - Speech: BM drafts., undated; 69646 (Box 32, Folder 574)
  - Living Over the Store: BM drafts., undated; 69645 (Box 32, Folder 575)
  - Forward, Carol Martin's book: BM drafts, correspondence, and photocopy., 1993, 1994; 69644 (Box 32, Folder 576)
  - David Mayer Introduction: BM draft, 2 pages., undated; 69643 (Box 32, Folder 577)
  - The Medicine Show: BM article from program book, Festival of American Folklife, Smithsonian Institution (1979)., 69642 (Box 32, Folder 578)
  - The American Medicine Show (Exhibit): Exhibition catalogue, The American Medicine Show, Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, December 1983 to February 1984; January 1984 issue of the Yale Weekly Bulletin and Calendar., 1983-1984; 69641 (Box 32, Folder 579)
  - The Medicine Show Log: Photocopy of BM article, "The Medicine Show Log: Reconstructing a Traditional American Entertainment.", 1984; 69640 (Box 32, Folder 580)
  - Medicine Show Performance: Playbill, poster., undated; 69639 (Box 32, Folder 581)
  - The Indian Medicine Show: Photocopy of BM article., 1971; 69638 (Box 32, Folder 582)
  - Lecturing to Accompany Paintings and Other Exhibits: Draft of BM talk, 3 pages., undated; 69637 (Box 32, Folder 583)
  - Step Right Up (dust jacket), undated; 69636 (Box 32, Folder 584)
  - Step Right Up (2nd edition advertisement), undated; 69635 (Box 32, Folder 585)
  - "Talking": BM draft, 50 pages., undated; 69634 (Box 32, Folder 586)
  - Up in All the Acts and Bits: Souvenir program for The Vi-ton-ka Medicine Show, and photocopy of BM article., 1983; 69633 (Box 32, Folder 587)
  - "You Are All Dying": Issue of journal Listening: Journal of Religion and Culture (1987) with BM article, "You Are All Dying": Illness and Death in the American Medicine Show; correspondence, photocopy., 69632 (Box 32, Folder 588)
  - TDR: Memoires of the Mouthpiece: Photocopies., 1986; 69631 (Box 32, Folder 589)
  - The Pageant Era: Issue of Theatre Crafts, Bicentennial Special Issue: History on Outdoor Stages (September 1975); photocopies., 69630 (Box 32, Folder 590)
  - Parody in Traditional American Entertainments: BM drafts., undated; 69629 (Box 32, Folder 591)
  - The Paterson Strike: BM article, "Paterson Strike Pageant," in TDR (Summer 1971)., 1975; 69628 (Box 32, Folder 592)
  - Performance Space: the Environmental Tradition: BM article in Architectural Association Quarterly (April/June 1975)., 69627 (Box 32, Folder 593)
  - Performance Studies…: BM talks and notes on the history and definition of Performance Studies., undated; 69626 (Box 32, Folder 594)
  - Popular Entertainment and the Community: BM draft., undated; 69625 (Box 32, Folder 595)
  - Popular Entertainment program at N.Y. State Museum, undated; 69624 (Box 32, Folder 596)
  - Popular Scenography: Photocopy of BM article., 1974; 69623 (Box 32, Folder 597)
  - An Interview with Percy Press: Photocopy of BM article, "An Interview with Percy Press and A Portfolio of Buskers.", 1975; 69622 (Box 32, Folder 598)
  - Public Celebrations in 19th century NY: BM draft., undated; 69621 (Box 32, Folder 599)
  - Reviews, Etc.: Articles, photocopies, reviews, clippings., undated; 69620 (Box 32, Folder 600)
  - Reviews of Books: Clippings, articles, drafts, correspondence., undated; 69619 (Box 32, Folder 601)
  - Day of Jubilee - Reviews and Nominations, 1997; 69618 (Box 32, Folder 602)
  - St. Patrick's Day - Talk: BM draft, 19 pages., undated; 69617 (Box 32, Folder 603)
  - "Scavengers of the Amusement World": BM article, "Scavengers of the Amusement World": Popular Entertainment and the Birth of the Movies, in exhibition catalogue, American Pastimes, Brockton Art Center - Fuller Memorial, Brockton, MA, January - April 1977., 69616 (Box 32, Folder 604)
  - Scene Design and Early Film: BM draft and photocopy of article., 1986; 69615 (Box 32, Folder 605)
  - Shubert Archive: Clippings, articles, photocopies, newsletters; BM draft; interview with Donald Flamm., undated; 69614 (Box 32, Folder 606)
  - Sam Shubert, Producer: BM draft, 16 pages., undated; 69613 (Box 32, Folder 607)
  - The Shuberts and "The Gladiola Girl": BM draft, 4 pages., undated; 69612 (Box 32, Folder 608)
  - The Shubert Brothers and the "Box-Office" Play: BM drafts, article published in Shubert Archive newsletter (1992) and LMDA Review (vol.5, no.1)., 69611 (Box 32, Folder 609)
  - The Shuberts as Theatre Builders: Draft, 15 pages., undated; 69610 (Box 32, Folder 610)
  - Shubert Archive Talk; Shubert Musicals Talk: BM drafts., undated; 69609 (Box 32, Folder 611)
  - "Something Glorious": BM drafts, notes, photocopies of article, "'Something Glorious': Greenwich Village and the Theater.", 1993; 69608 (Box 32, Folder 612)
  - The Stratford Jubilee: Photocopy of BM article, "'The Stratford Jubilee': Dram to Garrick's Vanity.", 1962; 69607 (Box 32, Folder 613)
  - Stuart Sherman's Third Spectacle: Draft and photocopy of BM article., 1976; 69606 (Box 32, Folder 614)
  - Tales from the Salesman's Golden Age: BM article in issue of TWA Ambassador: The Trans World Magazine (October 1975)., 69605 (Box 32, Folder 615)
  - Tamiment Playhouse: Draft of talk., undated; 69604 (Box 32, Folder 616)
  - "Theater" entry - Americana Annual, 1973: Clippings, photocopies, correspondence, BM notes and drafts, undated; 69603 (Box 32, Folder 617)
  - Theatre, American: BM draft, 17 pages., undated; 69602 (Box 32, Folder 618)
  - Vessel: The Scenography of Meredith Monk (Interview): BM article in TDR (March 1972), photocopies., 1972, 1974; 69601 (Box 32, Folder 619)
  - Virtual Fantasies Forward: BM draft, 2 pages., undated; 69600 (Box 32, Folder 620)
  - What Makes Theater?: BM article in Oculus, a publication by the American Institute of Architects, New York Chapter (June 1996)., 69599 (Box 32, Folder 621)
- Series IV: Anthologies [source materials]., 69576
  Series IV: Materials such as clippings, photocopied articles, notes, scripts, and correspondence relating to McNamara's Anthology of Popular Entertainments, as well as a British Play Anthology (1990) [21 folders.]
  - Anthology - misc. outtakes, etc.: Photocopies, articles, scripts, drafts., undated; 69597 (Box 32, Folder 622)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [I. Overview and Introduction]: Draft, correspondence, clipping, BM notes., 1989-1991; 69596 (Box 32, Folder 623)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [II. What the Butler Saw, 1969]: Clippings, photocopies., undated; 69595 (Box 32, Folder 624)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [III. The Changing Room, 1971]: Clippings, photocopies., undated; 69594 (Box 32, Folder 625)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [IV: Plenty, April 1978]: Clippings, photocopies., undated; 69593 (Box 32, Folder 626)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [V: Betrayal, November 1978]: Clippings, photocopies., 1980s; 69592 (Box 32, Folder 627)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [VI: Nicholas Nickelby, opening 1980]: Clippings, photocopies., undated; 69591 (Box 32, Folder 628)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [VII: Pack of Lies, 1983]: Clippings, photocopies., undated; 69590 (Box 32, Folder 629)
  - British Play Anthology 1990 [VIII: Theatre General]: Clippings, photocopies., undated; 69589 (Box 32, Folder 630)
  - P.E. Anthology: BM draft of his edited volume, American Popular Entertainments: Jokes, Monologues, Bits and Sketches., 1983; 69588 (Box 32, Folder 631)
  - Scenes (Acts, Bits, Etc.) D.: Scripts, photocopies, correspondence., undated; 69587 (Box 32, Folder 632)
  - "Brooks' Copy" [Jokes]: Scripts, photocopies, drafts., undated; 69586 (Box 33, Folder 633)
  - Brooks' Material for Matt Silverstein: Student work, bibliographies., 1972, 1973; 69585 (Box 33, Folder 634)
  - American Popular Entertainments [Book Draft, March 1983]: Drafts, correspondence., 69584 (Box 33, Folder 635)
  - Scetch Material: Photocopies, scripts., undated; 69583 (Box 33, Folder 636)
  - Jokes and Related Material: Draft, correspondence., undated; 69582 (Box 33, Folder 637)
  - Jokes, Quips, Rhymes, Comedy Songs, Comedy Dialogues; A.: Correspondence, scripts., undated; 69581 (Box 33, Folder 638)
  - Jokes Material: Articles, photocopies, scripts, notes, correspondence., undated; 69580 (Box 33, Folder 639)
  - Speeches, Recitations, Lectures, Pitches: Photocopies, drafts., undated; 69579 (Box 33, Folder 640)
  - Merry Muldoons, 1991 Revision: Clippings, articles, reviews, advertisements, correspondence, BM drafts and notes., 69578 (Box 33, Folder 641)
  - Miscellaneous - undated: Clippings, articles, photocopies, correspondence, bibliographies., 69577 (Box 33, Folder 642)
- Series V: Plays, written with Laurence Senelick., 69567
  Series V: Drafts and source materials for plays [8 folders].
  - Diary of a Provincial Lady, Final Copy: Drafts., 1984; 69575 (Box 33, Folder 643)
  - Mayhew's London, 3/22/84, Draft: Drafts, photocopies., 1984; 69574 (Box 33, Folder 644)
  - The London Poor: Draft., undated; 69573 (Box 33, Folder 645)
  - The London Poor (Through Darkest London) [series]: Drafts., 1984; 69572 (Box 33, Folder 646)
  - Through Darkest London: Draft., 1983; 69571 (Box 33, Folder 647)
  - Through Darkest London - publicity slides, fliers, photos, programs., undated; 69570 (Box 33, Folder 648)
  - Hiss the Villain, by Michael Booth: Photocopy., 1964; 69569 (Box 33, Folder 649)
  - Twentieth Century by Ben Hecht and Charles MacArthur: Script., undated; 69568 (Box 33, Folder 650)